<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-01T04:56:34-07:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aletha Labs</title><subtitle>A blog about Aletha Labs projects and insights in cybersecurity and programming</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Aletha Labs</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/09/30/welcome-to-aletha-labs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Aletha Labs" /><published>2025-09-30T17:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-09-30T17:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/09/30/welcome-to-aletha-labs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2025/09/30/welcome-to-aletha-labs/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="welcome-to-my-lab">Welcome to my lab</h2>

<h3 id="why-the-name">Why the name?</h3>

<p>I began in this space not knowing where to share my progress, research, and overall journey.
I started a <a href="https://github.com/AlethaLabs">GitHub</a> to begin sharing the programs and scripts I was working on, after that I needed a place to document all these new things I was learning.</p>

<p>Thus, Aletha Labs was born; my Great Grandmothers’ middle name was “Aletha” and she was a huge inspiration in my upbringing and I always looked up to her. Plus, I loved the sound, it is also derived from the ancient word - Aletheia - <strong><em>truth</em></strong>, which I think is fitting for this space.</p>

<h3 id="about-me">About Me</h3>

<p>I’m an apple farmer with a strong background in construction, and I’ve spent my entire adult life working in both fields. Farming has taught me patience, resilience, and the value of hard work, while construction has given me hands-on problem-solving skills and a mindset for building from the ground up.</p>

<p>Now, I’m channeling that same work ethic and curiosity into a new path: cybersecurity. I have been actively learning Python, Rust, and C, and I’m comfortable working with Linux systems. I learn best by doing—whether that’s writing programs, experimenting with system tools, or building projects that challenge me to grow.</p>

<h3 id="why-start-my-own-platform">Why Start My Own Platform?</h3>

<p>Being new to the <strong><em>vast ocean of tech</em></strong> can be quite intimidating. Do I document my personal journey in a platform such as medium, hacker news, or some generic blog site? LinkedIn articles are only good for introductory and highly formatted information, because at the end of the day it is a social-media platform, and people go there with a specific mindset.</p>

<p>I needed my own little section of the internet to thoroughly document my research. Plus, with a background in construction and farming, <strong><em>I love building and growing</em></strong>. It is what I do best and I would like to share that with the world.</p>

<h3 id="the-ultimate-vision-for-aletha-labs">The Ultimate Vision for <strong>Aletha Labs</strong></h3>

<p>I want this to eventually be a place for <strong><em>experienced and new</em></strong> people to share their research and findings. A place to create programs together that change the landscape of tech. Somewhere for <strong><em>all</em></strong> to build and grow.</p>

<p>— Chris</p>

<p><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-piccus-b287a2386">LinkedIn</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/AlethaLabs">GitHub</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="introduction" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to my lab]]></summary></entry></feed>